Wudi Gai

Phone:+85265658657

Email: gaiwudi2000@163.com / gaiwudi2000@gmail.com

Personal page: https://gaiwudi.github.io/

Objective:

I am interested in pursuing a career in bioinformatics research and other data analysis research, specifically in the areas of human and plant genomes, and the application of multi-omics approaches in biological research, or using code to solve the human life problem.

Education:

2019.09-2023.06, Bachelor of Agriculture degree in Horticulture, Northeast Agricultural University (211), Harbin, China. (GPA:85/100). There are genetics, biology, chemistry in my college courses.

Publication:

As the fourth author, following three co-authors, we have submitted an article that is currently undergoing a second review, IF>15, focusing on plant genome.

Experience:

2020.10-2022.10, I have led a Student Innovation Practical Training program titled 'Research on Blueberry Leaf Classification Based on Image Recognition' in Northeast Agricultural University. In this program, I collect the data of plant leaves. Then I use CNN to identify the type of these plants. During this time, I have learned the basic content related to AI, and can try to do model training, and have experience in AI.

2023.07-2023.10, Senior Sales Representative with Bayer Crop Science Co.in China.

From February to May 2023, I interned here as an intern, and later successfully became a regular employee. I am primarily responsible for the promotion and technical demonstration of pesticide products. And I travel to many places to take part in the local marketing campaigns.

2023.11-2024.05, Research Assistant at Institute of Advanced Agricultural Sciences of Peking University in the Weifang city, Shandong province, China.

In this institute, I mainly used Braker3, PASA, TransDecoder and other software to annotate genome, used GATK4 and other software to analyze resequencing data, used SyRi and other software to find and analyze genes of SV. After 6 months of scientific research training, I have a good understanding of the software used in bioinformatics, and can normally use python, R, and Bash.

2024.08-2024.10, Junior Research Assistant at The Chinese University of Hong Kong. In the CUHK, my major is bioinformatics in microbiome. I have used software (prokka, mafft and etc.) for bacteria analysis. I also know a little about the evolutionary tree for bacteria. Although I just work for a short time, I also learned how to analyse bacteria data, knowing the the difference

between eukaryotes and prokaryotes genome.

Skills:

Technical: Linux, shell, Python, PyTorch, Bash, R

Computer Vision, Plant Genomics, Bioinformatics.

For the other analysis using code, I can learn quickly combined my previous experience.

Languages:

English: I have passed the College English Test Level 6 (CET-6).

Mandarin: native.